Inventory of the Shaw Family Papers 1900-1963
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Shaw Family Papers circa 1900-1963
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2009.460
0.53
Shaw family; Shaw, Edna, b. 1920; Shaw, Hazel; Shaw, James arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 09/28/2009.
Biographical Note
Information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Shaw family.
Scope and Contents
Papers of the Shaw family of Skidmore, Missouri. Included are a scrapbook, 1941, of Edna Shaw (b. 1920) documenting her travels through some of the southern states where she directed the comedy "Bubbling Over," which was sponsored by the American Legion. It includes postcards and extensive handwritten descriptions by Edna Shaw, programs, and news clippings reviewing the play.Also included are a class photograph, 1900, presented to Edna's mother Hazel by her teacher, a 1904 letter addressed to Hazel Shutts, a small photo album (circa 1930s-1950s), correspondence, a wedding invitation, financial and insurance records, a Sigma Sigma Sigma sorority pledge manual, and a 1937 class will of the seniors of Skidmore High School.Also included is some genealogical information on the Shaw family (photocopies).
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Financial records; Photographs; Scrapbooks
Geographic Name:
Missouri--Social life and customs
Topical Term:
Account books.; Greek letter societies--Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Invitations.; Sigma Sigma Sigma; Women theatrical producers and directors; Women--Southern States--History.; Women--Travel.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- id61200 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1904-1954; id71040 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Genealogical Information, circa 1996; id71041 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Class of 1900 and OtherPhotographs, circa 1900; id71042 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financial Records, 1923-1945; id71043 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Class Will and Sigma Sigma Sigma Pledge Manual, circa 1937; id71044 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- id71021 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1941; id71037 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1941; id71038 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1941; id71039 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1941; id61201 (Box 2, Folder 4)